(忆往昔)
你毁了我的人生  奥莉薇特
You ruined my life, Olivette.
[咒语]
那是她吗
Is that her?
要我说  这才叫伸张正义
Poetic justice, if you ask me.
斯戴恩家族
The Styne family.
自我挖出了《诅咒之书》他们就一直在追踪我
They've been after me since I-I dug up "The Book of the Damned."
他们用的咒语
All the spells they used
都来自一本"极邪恶之书"
came from a book of "Unspeakable evil."
我的家族永远不会停止寻找那本书的
My family will never stop looking for that book.
你要想办法去掉迪恩的该隐血印
you got to figure a way to get the Mark of Cain off Dean
免得他再变回恶魔
before it turns him back into a demon?
那本书里的确有祛除血印的办法
There is a cure for the mark in the book.
但是有代价的
But it comes at a price.
我们得毁了它
We got to destroy it.
也许背着他做这些不是好主意
Maybe going behind his back ain't the best idea.
萨姆  烧了它  马上
Sam! Burn it -- now!
我知道这份生活就是如此
And I know it's the life --
做点坏事  才能做更多好事
Doing a little bad so you can do a lot of good.
你愿帮我吗
Will you help me?
但有时坏事非常严重
But sometimes the bad's real bad,
而好事  要付出相当大的代价
And the good -- it can come at one hell of a price.
杀了我儿子
Kill my son.
我替你杀了克劳力
I'll kill Crowley.
你能读懂这本书吗
Can you read the book?
把娜迪娅的法典拿来给我
Bring me Nadya's codex,
我马上就能把破咒办法告诉你
and I'll give you your cure.
我们达成了协议的
We had an agreement.
你想出去吗  快点干活儿吧
You want out? Hurry up.
(如今)
(内布拉斯加州  奥马哈)
你是艾琳吧
You must be Eileen.
是啊  我来面试的
Yes. I'm here for the interview.
谢谢你能下班后见我
Thank you so much for fitting me in after hours.
你可以看到  我身体健康
As, um, as you can see, I'm in good health
视力良好  这很重要  是吧
and my eyesight is 20/20, which is important, yes?
因为这是视力方面的研究
Because this is a research study on eyesight?
我朋友和我
M-my friends and I
都尽可能参与这些临床研究
do as many of these clinical studies as we can
因为我们都很穷
'cause we're all on budgets,
这种项目挣钱不少  可以付学费
and the money from these things really helps with college.
好的
Okay.
似乎没什么问题
Everything seems to be in order.
好的
Okay.
看看你的眼睛吧
Let's take a peek at these eyes.
好的
Yes.
好了
Okay.
不要
N-no! No!
No!
不要
No!!
里面没事吧
Everything okay in there?
怎么回事
What's going on?!
没什么事吧
Everything okay?
[邪恶力量 第10季第21集]
什么都没有
Nothing?
你什么都没破解出来
You've got nothing?!
罗威娜  这都多久了
Rowena, it's been days!
你说法典能顺利破解密文的
You said the codex would crack the code.
我是个艺术家  萨穆埃尔  这种事催不得
I am an artist, Samuel. These things cannot be rushed.
如果我不是被铐着...
Perhaps if I weren't chained up...
我现在不是最佳状态
I'm really not at full strength.
你休想达到最佳状态
Yeah, and you won't be at full strength.
不许施巫术
No witchcraft.
我需要从书中找到治好我哥哥的办法
Look, I need the cure for my brother from the book,
如果你在有意拖延
and if you're stalling...
我为什么要拖延啊
Why on earth would I stall?!
为了保护我自己  我也想祛除你哥哥的血印
I want the mark off your brother for my own protection!
我想摆脱这镣铐  离开这破地方
I want out of these chains and out of this pit,
我还希望你能遵守承诺
and I want you to hold up your end of the deal
杀了克劳力
and kill Crowley.
你还记得我们的协议吧  萨穆埃尔
You do remember the deal, do you not, Samuel?
相信我  我毫不介意杀了克劳力
Believe me, I have no issue killing Crowley!
问题是
The problem is,
娜迪娅在法典中用的语言
the language Nadya used in the codex
几乎无法破译
is damn near indecipherable.
她法术高强  但也十分自私
She was a gifted witch but a selfish pig.
她破解了一种密码
Once she cracked a code,
便又以自己的方式进行了编码
she then coded its secrets for herself.
那么
So...
那么我们要破译密文  还要先破译密文吗
Now we need to break a code to...break a code?
你真聪明
Quick, aren't you?
听着  迪恩的情况每况愈下
Listen, Dean gets worse every day.
赶紧做好
Get this done.
你不会忘记买东西吧
You won't forget the grocery shopping, will you?
不会
No.
(路易斯安那州  什里夫波特)
令人震惊
Astounding.
令人震惊又令人失望
Astounding and disappointing.
埃尔登
There was a time, Eldon,
我曾认为你是最有前途的一个
when I would call you our most promising.
去问问你的兄弟和堂表亲
You ask your brothers and your cousins.
但你显然是被宠坏了
But clearly, you have been spoiled and overindulged,
导致了如此自大
and the result is arrogance.
毫无判断力
The utter lack of judgment.
你采集器官前
You thought you'd take time
想跟那姑娘
for a little quickie with that girl
温存一番
before you harvested her.
-先生  -你被人看见了
- Sir... - And you were discovered by a witness.
我们不留目击者
We don't have witnesses!
也不留下尸体
And left a body behind.
采集器官时更不能留下尸体
And we certainly don't leave behind bodies when we harvest.
我们这么多世纪来得以成功的秘诀
The whole key to our success all these centuries
就是保密
is secrecy.
爸爸
Daddy...
我从未做过这样的事
I've never done anything like this before.
雅各布死后  我一直不在状态
I haven't been myself... ever since Jacob died.
不
Oh, no.
不不
No, no, no.
不许你玷污你哥哥的记忆
Don't you dare cheapen the memory of your brother
拿他当做自己愚蠢的借口
by using him as an excuse for your foolishness.
我十分后悔  先生
I'm filled with regret, sir.
我怎么不信
I doubt that.
但你会诚心后悔的
But you will be
如果你失去家族内的地位的话
if you are cast down to the lower echelons of this family,
被剥夺儿子和继承人的身份
where you will exchange your title of son and heir
变成小白鼠
for lab rat.
我就犯了这么一个错
I made this single mistake.
规矩
Discipline.
是维持我们共同生活的一切
It is all that holds our life together.
如果没有规矩  我们就完了
If it unravels, we are done.
你要这样赎罪
Here's how you'll redeem yourself.
首先  收拾好奥马哈的烂摊子
First, clean up your mess in Omaha.
然后  去找到这对温家兄弟
Next, you will track down these Winchesters
他们杀了你哥哥雅各布
who murdered your brother Jacob,
而且现在  他们可能还拿着
And who may now have in their possession
《诅咒之书》
"The Book of the Damned".
我会做到的
It will be done.
先生
Sir?
门罗叔叔
Uncle Monroe?
怎么  伊莱
Yes, Eli?
我在想  这样是否合适
I was wondering if it was best
让埃尔登处理如此重大的事
to put such an important assignment in Eldon's hands
毕竟
since his...
他的判断力如此有问题
judgment is so questionable.
你胆子不小啊  伊莱  你自己也有问题呢
That's very bold of you, Eli, considering your own issues.
我什么问题  先生
My issues, sir?
那个神秘的红发女孩
The mysterious redheaded girl
你堂兄雅各布死前在追查的那个
that your cousin Jacob was tracking when he died...
偷走了书的那个
the one that stole the book...
找到她的职责不是交给你了吗
was that task not passed on to you?
你找到她了吗
Have you located her?
我在努力  先生
I'm trying, sir.
还是没找到
There's still no trace of her.
如果书不在温家兄弟那里  就是在她那里
Well, if the Winchesters don't have the book, she's got it.
如果你真这么担心你堂弟会失败
So if you're so worried that your cousin will fail,
那就跟埃尔登汇报情况  帮助他
report in with Eldon and back his effort.
出去吧
Now get out.
你气色好差
Well, you look like crap on toast.
我没怎么睡好
I just haven't... really been sleeping well.
你是秘密结识了女人吗
There's a woman you haven't mentioned?
-女人  -我就是说
- A woman? - Well, I'm just saying.
我昨晚去睡的时候  你不在
You weren't here when I went to bed last night.
这几周经常一个人跑出去
You've been running off on your own a lot these past couple weeks.
我有时就这样
I do that.
才没有
You actually don't.
迪恩  我们又不是时刻同步的
Dean, we don't always do the exact same thing at the exact same time.
别忘了你还
Remember when you went off
自己跑去消灭了一窝吸血鬼
and snuffed that vampire nest by yourself?
那你是去剿灭吸血鬼巢穴了吗
Have you been snuffing vamps' nests?
不是
No, I-I...
怎么了  你这是干什么
What is that? What are you doing?
之前那些来找书的二货
So, those goons that were after the book,
斯戴恩家族
the, uh, the Stynes,
被杀的那个  说过自己有庞大的家族
well, the one that we killed said that he had a big family.
所以如果他们家还有别人  我就想我们该
So if there's more out there, I figure we should probably
尽可能多了解一下他们
get to know as much as we can about them.
怎么样
And?
就我们已经知道的那些
Well, there's pretty much what we do know,
他们操纵金融市场
that they screwed with financial markets,
帮助希特勒起家
they helped Hitler get started,
谁知道还有什么  或许迪斯科吧
along with god knows what else... probably disco.
但追溯到19世纪  就查不到什么了
But you go back to the 1800s, and the trail goes dead.
资料里没有  网上也找不到
There's nothing in the research, there's nothing online.
简直像他们家族有天从石头缝里蹦出来了
It's like the family just popped up one day.
家族一般不会这样的
Families don't usually do that.
是啊
No, they do not.
也不完全是浪费时间
Hasn't been a total waste of time, though.
我觉得我可能发现了桩案子
I think I caught us a case.
网上有一起奥马哈的凶杀案
There's a mention online of a murder in Omaha.
被害人眼睛被挖出
Victim's eyes were cut out.
清洁工跑进去  正好看到凶手从窗户跳下
Janitor runs in just as the killer jumps out the window.
-就这样吗  -三楼窗户
- That's it? - Well, the window was on the third story.
我只是想找点事做
Look, man, I'm just trying to stay busy here, okay?
除非你有更要紧的事
Unless you have bigger fish to fry.
没有  你说得对
No, I-I'm sold.
我去
I'm in.
好  我去睡了
All right, well, I'm gonna hit it.
你也该睡会儿
You probably should, too.
我们明天一早就走
We'll leave first thing in the a.m.
查理
Hey, Charlie.
真是你啊
It is you.
虽然开着老旧的小轿车
Uh, in a...beat-up, prehistoric subcompact.
我们为什么在这里见面
But why are we meeting here?
我可以去死星的啊
I could've come to the death star.
不...
No, no, this is, uh...
这样其实更好
This is better, actually.
我们反正也不在地堡里工作
We're not gonna be working in the bunker, so...
到底是什么事来着
What is this about, again?
你没怎么说明白
You were kind of...vague.
是这样的  迪恩的情况并没好转
Okay, so, here's the thing... Dean is not getting any better.
我觉得我们如果不祛除血印
I feel like if we don't get the mark off his arm,
他会被吞噬的
it's gonna eat him up.
这我明白  但我们要怎么办
I get it, but what are we gonna do about it?
我拿到了一本法典  算是超自然
I got ahold of a codex which is sort of a-a collection
译码工具全集吧
of supernatural code-breaking tools,
应该能用来破译《诅咒之书》
and it should help crack "The Book of the Damned."
那太好了
That would be awesome
只是书已经
if the book, you know,
被毁了
actually existed.
没被毁
It does.
我
Uh, I, um...
我假装烧掉之前把书掉包了
I swapped it out right before it looked like I burned it.
好吧  迪恩是想烧掉的  那他生气吗
Okay. Well, Dean wanted it burned, so is he pissed?
当然了  他还不知道
Of course. He doesn't know.
天呐  你们俩
Geez! The two of you.
查理  他不在状态
Charlie, he's not himself.
真的  他会阻止我的
He's not. He would try and stop me.
他已经放弃了
He's given up.
我请了一位专家  用法典进行破译
Look, I called in an expert to... to use the codex,
但法典也是加了密的
but it turns out it's sort of...encoded also,
所以我想让你帮忙  加速进展
so I thought you might help... move things along faster.
背着迪恩
Behind Dean's back.
而迪恩已经警告我们
After Dean told us
我们如果瞎鼓捣  会被书整惨的
the stupid book would kick our asses if we mess with it.
这里面有一点没问题的地方吗
I-- is there any part of this that doesn't reek?
我有没有提到
Did I mention you'll be working
你要跟世上最危险的女巫之一合作
with one of the most dangerous witches in the world?
这样不好吧  萨姆
I don't know, Sam.
就我所知  这是...
As far as I can tell, this is...
救他的唯一机会了
our only shot at saving him.
如果我们不抓住
If we don't take it...
他就没救了
he's gone.
我不是说得很清楚吗  萨穆埃尔
I thought I was clear, Samuel.
我要的是更多时间  不是助手
I requested more time, not an assistant.
我不也说得很清楚吗  罗威娜
And I thought I was clear, Rowena.
查理不是你的助手
Charlie is not your assistant.
你是她的助手
You're hers.
你在哪学的魔法
And you studied your craft where?
主要是在一个叫马斯爪哇的馆子
Mostly a joint called mas java.
无线信号特别好
It has excellent wi-fi.
我从未听过那个地方
I have not heard of this institution,
而且全球各处的巫术中心我都知道
and I know all the great global centers of witchcraft.
也有道理  我不是女巫嘛
Makes sense, 'cause I'm not a witch.
我是技术宅
I'm a nerd.
技术宅的聚集地我都知道
And I know all the great centers of nerddom.
罗威娜  地盘标记完了吗
Rowena, are you done marking your turf?
听着  查理有技术手段
Listen, Charlie has tech chops
能加速娜迪娅法典的破解
that'll speed up cracking Nadya's codex.
你辨识出古咒语
You will spot the ancient curses and spells,
把这堆乱码变成明文
and that'll put this whole mess in context.
小卡
Cass.
你也知道这事吗
Are you in on this, too?
老天爷
Hell's bells.
又来人
More distractions?
你是什么
What are you?
女巫还是技术宅
Witch or nerd?
是天使
Angel.
什么
Beg pardon?
卡西迪奥  有法力
Castiel has, uh, powers...
可以用神力保护你们的工作
Spiritual muscle that'll help safeguard the work.
防备什么
Safeguard it from what?
你
You.
我不能一直待在这里做仲裁
I can't be here full time to referee.
我就能吗
And I can?
是的  拜托了
Yes. Please.
帮我这个忙
Please do this for me.
有什么规则
Well, what are the rules?
既然我要仲裁  我至少该清楚规则
If I'm gonna referee, I should at least know them.
你真是一根筋啊
Quite literal, aren't you?
他知道首要规则是
Does he know that the first rule
别告诉你哥哥我们在做什么吗
is don't tell your brother what we're doing?
迪恩不知道吗
Dean doesn't know?
萨姆  这事不会有好果子的
Sam, this never ends well.
我也这么说
That's exactly what I said.
大家都别紧张
Okay, everyone take a breath.
现在局面很糟
Look, we're up against it, okay?
我们都经历过这种情况
And we've all been up against it before,
也知道有时候所有的选择都很糟糕
and we know there are times when every choice sucks.
我们瞒着迪恩
Now, us...lying to Dean...
是糟糕程度最低的选择
is the choice that sucks the least.
我们必须成功
We have to make this work.
求你们了
Please.
好吧
Okay, yeah.
为了迪恩
For Dean.
小卡
Cass?
好
Okay.
为了迪恩
For Dean.
我跟他不熟啊
Barely know the man.
希望是要事
I hope this is important.
我玩得正嗨呢
I have a perfect game going.
出现了一个问题  陛下
T-t-there's a problem, majesty.
我真希望你们这群蠢货能给我带来一次好消息
Just for once, I wish you trolls would bring me some good news.
陛下  密苏里州生疖子了
"Sire, Missouri has boils."
让人开心的消息
Something cheerful.
是陛下的母亲
It's your majesty's mother.
我母亲怎么了
What about my mother?
她失踪了
Wh-- uh, s-she's missing.
什么
What?
听过杀死信使这一说吗
You've heard of killing the messenger?
没有我母亲的消息别回来
Don't come back without news of my mother.
闭嘴
Shut up.
组合好棒
Nice grouping.
警察告诉我不得任何人入内
Police told me no one was allowed in.
但联调局不包含在内  是吧
That didn't mean the FBI, right?
清洁工是在人被杀之后马上赶来的吗
And the janitor came in right after the killing?
是的  他听到了尖叫
Yeah, he heard screaming...
可能是她眼球被挖出时发出的吧
Maybe when her eyeballs were scooped out.
清洁工看到他跳下了窗
Janitor saw a man jump out the window,
跑进了小巷
run down the alley.
跑
Running?
跳下三层楼后吗
After, uh... falling three stories?
看上去是这样
That's what it looked like.
-有监控录像吗  -嗯
- Security footage? - Yeah, sure.
但只有一个摄像头拍到东西了
Uh, but just one of them caught any action.
在巷子里
Out in the alley.
这是租下办公室的家伙
That's the guy who rented the office.
三楼跳下来还挺悠然啊
That's pretty slick for a three-story drop.
等等  能重放一下吗
Wait a second. Can you, uh, play it again?
嗯
Yeah.
继续
Keep going.
停住
Okay, freeze there.
放大
Zoom in.
跟斯戴恩家族的纹身一样
Same ink as the Stynes.
他租下这里多久了
How long was he renting here?
一个月
Uh, just a month.
但我只见过他一两天
But I only saw him a day or so.
是在进行临床试验  招募学生志愿者
Some sort of clinical trial using student volunteers.
他没说到要用眼球
He didn't mention eyeballs.
你今后恐怕要多问一句了吧
Well, I guess you're gonna ask about that from now on, huh?
失陪
Excuse me.
(卡西迪奥来电)
你如果再记起来什么
Listen, you, uh, remember anything else,
给我们打电话
give us a call.
电话推销
Telemarketer.
你话挺多啊
You're quite the chatty patty.
你跟他俩说什么了
What'd you tell those two?
没说什么
Hardly anything.
没什么  我没说什么
Nothing. I-I've got nothing to say.
我不信
I don't believe you.
(无匹配)
该死
Damn it.
你那个神奇的机器
That miraculous machine of yours
还没破解一切吗
hasn't solved everything by now?
真是中看不中用
Overrated, I'd say.
我在利用电脑
I'm using the computer
分析书加密的规律
to find some pattern in the book's coding
或者与娜迪娅法典是否有相近之处
or any synchronicity with the symbols in Nadya's codex.
我比较传统
I'm more old-school.
我解读自然向我展示的预示
I read the signs nature shows me...
在有人之前  那些力量曾掌控世界
the forces that ruled before there was man.
我怎么没想到啊
Why didn't I think of that?
听上去你俩血糖都降低了
Okay, it sounds like blood sugar is dipping in here.
我买了零食
I got snacks.
我做人的时候
When I was human,
我特别喜欢这些猪皮脆
I grew very fond of these pork rinds.
你了解写下《诅咒之书》的那个女人吗
What do you know about the chick who wrote "The Book of the Damned"?
艾格尼丝是位隐居的修女
Agnes was a hermit nun...
十分疯狂
and as mad as a hatter.
一心想破解咒语
Made it her business to undo curses.
就像留下该隐血印的那个
Like the one that caused the Mark of Cain.
与所有正邪较量一样
As in any struggle between good and evil,
必须达到平衡
balance is required.
为破解一个诅咒
To cure one curse,
艾格尼丝要知道如何施另一个咒
Agnes had to know how to inflict another.
这两者在魔法世界是共存的
They live side-by-side in the magic world.
相互依存
One cannot be without the other.
是啊  就像二元系
Sure, sure. Like, uh, a binary system.
我得按照隐士的方式思考了
So, I got to think like a hermit nun.
我说过她被人活活烧死了吗
Did I mention they burned her alive?
谁
"They"?
她弄了一堆咒语  又看到撒旦预兆
A cornucopia of curses and satanic visions
教会当然会发现
did not go unnoticed by the church hierarchy.
他们绝不会轻饶不守规矩的修女
These men would not abide a rogue nun.
可怜的艾格尼丝
Poor Agnes.
超前于时代啊
Ahead of her time.
跟你我一样
Much like you and I.
好了
Well...
我可不觉得我们很像
I actually don't...see our similarities all that much.
因为善良年轻  而我老迈邪恶吗
Because you're young and good and I'm ancient and evil?
是因为这个吗
Is that it?
怎么了
What?
我跟你说说你吧
Let me tell you about you...
童年艰辛孤独
A difficult and lonely childhood.
十分凄惨  父母不在
Tragedy, absent parents.
总不入流
Always outside the mainstream.
性方面很主动
Sexually progressive.
生活在自己的小世界里  寻求清净和人生方向
Living in your own head for solace and direction.
是啊  但我们还是很不一样的
Yeah, but still, we are pretty different.
我一看见你就看透了你
I read you the minute I saw you.
我想你也渐渐知道了
And I'm sure you're learning
正邪的分界线是很模糊的
that the line between good and evil is quite flexible.
但盲目的忠诚是我们的最大区别
But we part company when it comes to blind devotion.
比如  温家兄弟
Case in point... the Winchesters.
你把他们当做了你缺失的亲人
You've made them the family you don't have.
愚蠢
Foolish.
萨姆和迪恩就像我哥哥一样
Sam and Dean are like my brothers.
我爱他们
I love them.
我知道
I know.
这份坚定的忠诚会害了你  姑娘
And that steadfast loyalty will be your undoing, my girl.
斯戴恩家族为什么要
So, why would the Stynes be
挖眼杀人啊
actually up to the eyeballs in murder?
有什么联系
What's the connection?
干掉一个斯戴恩  千千万万个蹦出来
Well, when you take a few Stynes down, more pop up.
天知道他们有多少
I mean, how many are there?
我只想说  我很庆幸我们烧毁了书
All I can say is, I'm glad we burned that damn book.
至少他们休想拿到那个了
At least they can't get their mitts on that.
是啊
Yeah.
你呢  你怎么样了
Uh, what about you? How you doing?
那个事吗
Oh, you mean the thing?
-嗯  -嗯
- Yeah. - Yeah.
有些黑暗的念头  可怕的幻视  暴力的冲动
You know, some dark thoughts, creepy visions, violent urges.
跟往常一样
Same old same old.
幸好有桩案子可以关注
I'm happy I got a murder to focus on, though.
(卡西迪奥来电)
小卡
Cass?
萨姆
Sam.
不  是迪恩
No, it's Dean.
-什么事  -没事
- What's up? - Nothing.
我就是想...保持联络
I'm just, uh... Just staying in touch.
我一向如此啊
Like I do.
有心事吗
Something on your mind?
没有
No.
这通电话毫无意义
This call is pointless.
我的车到了
My ride's here.
冰箱都空了
The fridge is picked clean.
你去买  我掏钱
Your turn to fly. I buy.
那是我的吧
That's, uh, that's mine, right?
你最近跟小卡有联络吗
Hey, uh, you talk to... talk to Cass recently?
没有啊  好一阵没联络了
No. Um, not for a while.
怎么了
Why?
就是不知道他干什么呢
I was just wondering what he's up to.
他肯定有事在做吧
He's got to be up to something, right?
嗯
Yeah.
天使的事吧
Angel stuff or...
我也不知道
I don't know.
嗯
Yeah.
好了  我要披萨
All right, I vote for pizza.
嗯
Yes.
是啊  罗威娜是很麻烦
Yes, Rowena is a handful.
天呐  在床上放蛇
Oh, mercy. Snakes in the bed?
那的确会让我发狂
That would set my teeth on edge.
如果我有床
If I owned a bed.
或是睡觉的话
Or slept...ever.
我知道啦
Look, I get it.
她不讨喜  她可恶极了
She's unpleasant. She's horrible.
工作的地方还乱七八糟
She has a messy workstation.
还有什么内幕
What's the dirt?!
她一定还有什么我不知道的秘密
There must be something that I don't know about her,
可以让我用作筹码的
something I could hold over her as a bargaining chip.
一个恶魔情人
A demon lover?
不用说得那么详细
You don't need to paint a picture.
还有别的吗
Is there anything else?
是吗
Really?
确定吗
You sure?
给我来个人
I need a minion!
我们把地球都翻遍了  陛下  昼夜不歇
We are scouring the planet, sire, a-around the clock.
不找到您母亲  我们绝不停
We will not rest until your mother is found.
当然了
I should say you aren't.
我另有任务交给你
And I have another mission for you.
-好的  陛下  -马上给我找到此人
- Yes, sire. - Locate this person -- immediately.
不管花什么代价
I don't care what it takes.
失败  就等着无尽的折磨吧
Fail on pain of infinite pain.
马上去办  陛下
On it, your majesty.
还愣着干吗
You're still here.
身边尽是庸才
Surrounded by mediocrity.
我还这么坚挺真是奇迹
It's a wonder I stay so buoyant.
(24小时披萨外卖)
好了  别过来了
All right, hold it right there.
站住
Hold it.
我说了  站住
I said, "hold it."
我已经尽全力了
I am doing my best,
但她在旁边挖苦我  监视我
but with her criticizing, breathing down my neck,
还企图拉拢我
trying to sign me up for team witch --
哀叹1723年的音乐才是好音乐
and moaning how the one good year for music was 1723 --
我要抓狂了
I -- I am going crazy.
-我知道  -不  她是个坏人
- I know. - No, I mean, she is evil.
她就是邪恶女巫嘛  所以说起来
She is a wicked witch, so by definition --
不不  我的意思是
No, no, no, I mean
这样下去会出事的
something bad is gonna happen here.
卡西迪奥  把我带去别的地方吧
Castiel, man, just spring me for two hours,
一两小时就行  安静的地方
one hour -- anyplace quiet.
迪恩是我朋友  我不能搞砸
Dean is my buddy, and I cannot screw this up,
但我的脑子  就像装满了毛虫糖
but -- but my mind is -- is -- it's a wad of gummy worms.
求你了
Please.
现在是这样的
Here's how this works.
你是挺厉害  我看得出
You're strong. I'll give you that.
但你也是人  会流血  会疼
But you can bleed and hurt just like the next guy,
所以我来问  你要答
so I'm gonna ask questions, you're gonna give answers,
不然很快就会很不好看了
or it's gonna get crazy real quick.
那但愿你有充足的时间
Well, I hope you got some time.
我可不是普通的小猫咪
I'm not the usual breed of cat.
我们也不是
Neither are we.
是不是你杀了奥马哈的那个姑娘
Did you kill that girl in Omaha?
是的
Yeah.
那么是真的了
So, it's true.
你有该隐血印
You have the mark of Cain.
深表同情
My sympathies.
所以你才想要那本书
That's why you wanted the book --
把血印去掉
to remove it.
我们想要书
We wanted the book
是因为那是你们的力量之源
because that's where your power comes from.
我们的家族事业
See, our family business
就是让你们这种人衰败陷落
is putting guys like you out of business.
真令人钦佩
It's impressive.
我来说说我们的家族事业吧
Let me tell you about my family business.
你们根本无法想象
You're in way over your heads.
我们家族庞大无比  遍布全世界
The family is vast -- spread over the world.
你提到的力量
And that power that you mentioned
并不源自那本书
doesn't come from the book.
而是源自人的智慧和意愿
It comes from intelligence and will.
书只起到辅助作用
The book facilitates.
股市跳水  大萧条  911事件
Stock market dive, recession, 9/11 --
想起什么了吗
any of them ring a bell?
阿拉伯之春(反政府运动)
Arab spring.
根本毫不费力
Didn't even break a sweat.
好吧
Okay.
为什么
Why?
不入虎穴焉得虎子  伙计们
Well, you got to be in it to win it, boys.
混乱引发恐惧
You see, chaos breeds fear.
恐惧孕育恐慌  恐慌演变成绝望
Fear breeds panic, and panic breeds desperation,
而绝望中总能捞到利润
and there's always profit to be made from desperation.
引发的混乱有多大  就有多大的残局要收拾
You make a big enough mess, has to get cleaned up.
我们干解决麻烦这一行已经一千年了
And we've been in the fix-it business for 1,000 years,
现在生意正蒸蒸日上
and business has never been better.
不过过去80年里  我们没有了书
Now, for the last 80 years, we haven't had the book.
有书在手  我们会所向披靡
With the book, we're unstoppable.
小卡  怎么了  长话短说
Cass, what's going on? Make it quick.
你杀的那个姑娘
The girl you killed --
为什么要拿走她的眼珠
why take her eyes?
那件事
That whole situation --
很不幸
unfortunate.
采集的时候  我们一般不会留下尸体的
We normally never leave a body when we harvest.
你们干什么
When you what?
这是我们的家族特点
It's a family specialty --
生物工程
bioengineering.
外科增强
Surgical enhancement.
我说的可不是隆鼻
And I'm not talking about nose jobs.
看见了吗
See?
里面有两颗心
Two hearts in here.
还有额外的肌肉  尤其在腿部
Bunch of extra muscle, especially in the legs.
家族的每位成员都有自己的特殊之处
Every man in the family's had a little something.
不过也不出意料
Pretty much what you'd expect, though,
考虑到我们的先祖
given the family tree.
斯戴恩家族吗
The Stynes?
真正的先祖
The real family tree.
名字做了必要的改动
The name was altered out of necessity.
你无意中发现了一族
You have chanced upon a lineage
历史悠久  有光荣传统的家族
with a long and proud tradition...
也有些讨厌的恶名
and some unwanted notoriety.
是欧洲最古老的家族之一
One of Europe's oldest families.
我们家族是
The house of...
弗兰肯斯坦
Frankenstein.
-让我集中精力  -历史上最伟大的女巫
- Let me focus. - The greatest witches of history
都咨询过我的意见
have sought my counseling.
我愿意和你合作  你却不理我
Yet you spurn me when I offer myself as collaborator!
天啊  真是...
Oh, my god! This is --
我觉得我没说清楚
I don't think I'm making myself clear.
这里出状况了
I've got a -- I've got a situation here.
不能让查理独自一人出去
There's no way Charlie can go off by herself.
小卡  很多非常凶恶的人都在找她
Cass, there are dangerous people looking for her.
好吧  那我陪她
Fine. I'll go with her.
不  你也不能把罗威娜一个人留在那儿
No, you -- you can't leave Rowena alone, either.
现在毫无进展
Nothing is getting done.
那就把她们分开  小卡  尽力而为吧
Then separate them, Cass. Just do the best you can.
弗兰肯斯坦不是真的
Frankensteins aren't real.
只是故事
They're made up.
是啊  当然
Yeah, of course.
我们家族也不认识什么玛丽·雪莱(小说作者)
And we never had a family acquaintance named Mary Shelley
她在弗兰肯斯坦城堡待了几晚
who spent a few nights in castle Frankenstein
无意发现了我们的秘密
and stumbled upon our secrets,
逼得我们只好隐姓埋名
and forced us to change our name and go underground.
那雪莱为什么没把你们的秘密公之于众
So, why didn't Shelley go public?
她都写了本书了
She wrote a book.
还要怎么公之于众
Doesn't get more public than that.
但没人相信那是真的
But no one believed it to be true,
就像也不会有人相信你的话
just like no one's gonna believe you.
只要我和我弟弟相信
Well, as long as my brother and me believe,
就够了
that's enough.
是啊
Yeah, well...
虽然你们这个小家族挺强的
as mighty as I'm sure your little family is,
但我们家族才是世界的主宰
mine is a juggernaut.
我们不是普通人
We're not ordinary men.
我们是斯巴达式的勇士
We're spartans.
但你们并非永生
But you aren't immortal.
我们是可牺牲的
What we are is expendable.
我倒下  还有千千万万的后补兵团
I go down, there's an army of replacements behind me.
那这个兵团的大本营在哪呢
And where does this army call home, hm?
谁是怪物老爹
Who's big daddy Frankenstein?
你没听我说吗  我们隐姓埋名了
Were you here when I mentioned that we're underground?
这都是秘密
There are secrets.
我特别擅长挖掘秘密
Well, I'm swell at uncovering secrets.
你把书给我
You give me the book,
我们就可以聊一聊
and it's conceivable that we could have a conversation.
书
The book?
老兄  我们没有书
Dude, we don't have the book.
书被烧毁了
The book was burned.
书被咒语保护了
The book is protected by a spell.
是无法毁灭的
It's eternal.
不可能被摧毁
It cannot be destroyed.
听着  小卡  我得回去了
Look, Cass, I got to get back.
你解决一下
Handle this.
我会尽快过去的
I'll be there as soon as I can.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
出事了
Something came up.
-什么事  -解决了
- What? - It's handled.
里面情况如何  有得到什么信息吗
Uh, what's going on in there? Get any more out of him?
是的  有好多呢
Yeah, an earful -- truly.
我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
我的天  他拧断胳膊逃走了
Oh, my god. He ripped it off.
独处时间
Alone time?
她为什么需要独处时间
Why does she need alone time?
要我说太自以为是了
Bit of a prima donna, if you ask me.
这姑娘真的不行
The girl is simply out of her league.
没有我  会毫无进展的
Without me, the work grinds to a halt.
罗威娜
Rowena.
她需要安静
She needs quiet.
她现在压力很大
She's under a lot of pressure,
而且又感觉在背叛朋友  所以更难受
and it doesn't help that she feels like she's betraying her friend.
背叛
Betrayal.
她会克服的
She'll get over it.
一旦她有了自己的孩子
Once she has children of her own,
她就会知道什么叫背叛
she'll know all about betrayal.
你有孩子
You have a child?
我有孩子吗
Do I have a child?
也就地狱之王而已
The king of hell. That's all.
王
The king.
克劳力是你儿子
Crowley is your son?
怪不得呢
Well, that explains a lot.
带他一定很不容易吧
I'm sure that was quite a challenge.
继续工作吧  我们在这里浪费时间呢
Well, back to it, eh? We're wasting time in here.
我去看看她怎样了
I'm gonna... see how she's doing.
查理
Charlie?
(黑鸟旅馆)
我知道她在哪
I know where she is.
如果你愿意  我可以替你解决
Now, I can take care of it for you, if you want.
是我的荣幸
It'd be my pleasure.
不
No.
我得解决这事
I need to handle this.
地址给我
Give me the location.
你有笔吗
Well, you got a pencil?
快说
Just spill.
一个叫做黑鸟旅馆的破地方
A dump called the Blackbird Motel.
登记在卡莉·阿西莫夫名下
Registered under the name Carrie Asimov.
有他踪迹吗
Any sign of him?
很多踪迹  但看不到他
Lot of signs -- just no him.
我跟着血迹
I followed the blood trail --
都要流成密西西比河了
which, by the way, was like the mississippi --
直到血迹消失
till it ran dry.
什么意思  流血而死了吗
Meaning what? He bled out?
意思是踪迹中断了
Meaning that the trail stopped.
消失了  没啦
Vanished. Nada.
他一定是认为他能打败我们
He sure must have thought he was gonna win that one,
他可说了不少呢
'cause, phew, was he gabby.
我查阅了一切
Well, I've been going through
有关弗兰肯斯坦家族的资料
everything we have on the Frankensteins,
就跟埃尔登说的一样
and it's just like Eldon said.
一千年令人不快的历史
I mean, 1,000 years of nasty.
他们收拾黑死病的烂摊子挣了很多钱
They made a ton mopping up the black plague.
挑起了百年战争
They started the 100 years war.
我之前想  "斯戴恩家人真多"
You know, I thought, "Man, there's a lot of them Stynes."
就像是猛男中心一样
You know, it's like, uh, alpha-male central.
然后我就想到  这部分是关键
And then I thought -- and this is key --
我就想  "这很糟
I thought, "This is bad,
但如果这些人拿到书  那就糟透了
but it would really blow if these guys had the book.
至少他们没能拿到书"
At least they don't have the damn book."
是啊  是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
至少那该死的书被烧了
At least the damn book burned.
对吗  萨姆
Right, Sam?
但随后  埃尔登·弗兰肯斯坦
But then, Eldon Frankenstein --
他告诉我一个有趣的事实
he hits me with this little fun fact.
他说这书是不能被摧毁的
He says that the book can't be destroyed.
说这书是不能被切碎  剁碎
Says that it can't be sliced, diced,
撕碎  烧毁  淹没的
shredded, burned, drowned.
不能被摧毁
Cannot be destroyed.
是不是很疯狂
Ain't that crazy?
因为
Because...
我知道我看到有东西被烧了
I know I saw something burn.
萨姆  给我接  否则...
Sam, you answer that, so help me...
-萨姆  她不见了  -谁不见了
- Sam, she's gone. - Who's gone?
我到处找了
I've looked everywhere.
查理不见了
Charlie is gone.
以西结  7个字母
Ezekiel -- seven letters.
7代表搜寻人
Seven represents the seeker.
(无匹配)
好吧
Okay.
圣徒代表字母组合
Saints represent groups of letters
代表了数字
that represent numbers...
代表概念  是由...
that stand for concepts represented by...
(匹配)
我也许是个天才
I might be a genius.
我知道你在里面  阿西莫夫小姐
I know you're in here, Miss Asimov.
你手里有我想要的
You have it. I want it.
我真不敢相信
I don't freakin' believe it!
你又把查理牵扯了进来
You got Charlie involved with this again,
现在她还失踪了
and now she's missing?!
查理  你在哪
Charlie, where are you?
一个旅馆  黑鸟旅馆
Um, a -- a motel -- t-t-the Blackbird.
萨姆  有人来了
Sam, someone is here.
他们觉得书在我手里
T-t-they think I have the book.
如果书在你手里就给他们
If you have the book, give it to them.
《诅咒之书》在查理那里
Charlie has the damn "Book of the Damned"?
没有
No, I don't have it.
我只带着笔记
I just -- I-I just -- I have my notes.
那就把笔记给他们  查理
Then give them your notes, Charlie!
把密码给他们  他们想要什么都给他们
Give them the code -- whatever they want!
查理  我不知道到底怎么回事
Charlie, I don't know what the hell is going on,
但你得听我的
but you need to listen to me.
不管是谁想要什么  你立刻给他们  明白吗
Give whoever that is whatever they want. You understand?
(上传文件)
查理
Charlie?!
我做不到  迪恩
I can't do that, Dean.
(上传完成)
(发送)
书一直都在你那里
So, you had the book the whole time?
-迪恩  -当着我的面撒谎
- Dean -- - Lied right to my face.
我以为这是让你摆脱血印的唯一机会
I thought it was our only chance to get you free of the mark,
所以我就抓住了
so I grabbed it.
我的意思我已经说得很清楚了
I made it real clear how I felt.
你有考虑过吗
You ever consider that?
迪恩  听着
Dean, listen --
你还把小卡牵扯进来
And then you pulled Cass into it.
还有查理
And Charlie.
查理爱你  迪恩
Charlie loves you, Dean.
我们都爱你
We all love you.
你要把属于我的东西给我
You're gonna give me what's mine.
属于我和我家族的
Mine and my family's.
天哪
Oh, god.
查理
Charlie?